<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<EmailTemplate xmlns="http://soap.sforce.com/2006/04/metadata">
    <available>true</available>
    <description>New Email Template setup in June 2012</description>
    <encodingKey>ISO-8859-1</encodingKey>
    <letterhead>Master</letterhead>
    <name>INSTRUMENTAL LESSONS AND MUSIC DEPARTMENT ENSEMBLES AND ACTIVITIES</name>
    <style>freeForm</style>
    <subject>Instrumental Lessons and Music Department Ensembles and Activities</subject>
    <textOnly>The International School
of Moscow
Part of The British Schools Group



Dear Parents,



INSTRUMENTAL LESSONS AND MUSIC DEPARTMENT ENSEMBLES AND ACTIVITIES



ISM aims to offer all students as many opportunities to be involved in music making ensembles and offers regular performance opportunities throughout the calendar. I am writing to you to outline some of the activities available to students this year.



Instrumental Lessons (Individual)



All students have the option of studying a musical instrument through individual lessons with visiting teachers. Please click here to download the lesson request form for the Autumn term. Please read this information carefully and if you have any question or wish to know more do not hesitate to contact me. As the administration of the lessons is very complex we regret we cannot accept any late applications. Please return the form on time to avoid disappointment.



Orchestral Instruments Taster sessions Wednesday 11th September 9am-11am



If you and/or your child are unsure on whether they wish to learn an instrument or need more advice on which to choose some of our visiting teachers will be offering taster session on Wednesday 11th September. Students, if they wish, will get the opportunity to go to the music department to try some of the instruments. This year we are focusing on increasing uptake of Woodwind and Brass instruments. Trumpet, Clarinet, Flute and Violin will be available to try out on the 11th September.



Lunchtime and after school Music ensembles. ALL START WEEK BEG 23rd September



Years 1-3

An after school Choir (Part of ISM after school activities) runs throughout the year led by Miss Hodgson. You will receive further information regarding this in our After School Activities Programme future correspondence.

Year 4-6

A lunchtime choir will run on Thursday Lunchtime every fortnight. All students from Year 4,5 &amp; 6 are welcome to come along.
Students from year 4-6 are welcome to join the senior school orchestra on Friday Lunchtime if they have already been learning an instrument for at least a year.

Year 7-11

School orchestra led by Mr Riley-Gledhill and Mr Langford will rehearse on Friday Lunchtime in the music room. All instrumentalists welcome.
Senior choir with Mr Langford and Ms Kudryaseva will rehearse after school on Thursdays until 5pm. This is open by audition to new students and an extra bus service is available for this session. Please see the separate letter attached for more information on this.

Please do not hesitate to contact me should you require any further information about music activities at ISM.



Yours Sincerely





James Langford



Music &amp; Drama Teacher

james.langford@internationalschool.ru



The International School of Moscow
World Class Education

__________________________________________________________
Member of The British School Group- University of Cambridge Examination Centre  - Affiliate Member of the Conference of British International Schools - Licensed by the Russian Ministry of Education</textOnly>
    <type>html</type>
    <uiType>Aloha</uiType>
</EmailTemplate>
