<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<EmailTemplate xmlns="http://soap.sforce.com/2006/04/metadata">
    <available>true</available>
    <encodingKey>ISO-8859-1</encodingKey>
    <letterhead>ISM</letterhead>
    <name>Weekly Update 31st May, 2012</name>
    <style>freeForm</style>
    <subject>Weekly Update 31st May, 2012</subject>
    <textOnly>Dear Parents,

We have some interesting information, a small request and an important reminder for you this week, so please take the time to have a read of our last Weekly Update for May, 2012.......

1. Survey Reminder

We kindly ask you to fill out our annual questionnaire (please find the link below). Your feedback will be used for future planning. We value your comments enormously and hope that you will find the time to answer a couple of short questions. The survey will be available until 4th June, 2012. It would be appreciated if you could complete the comments boxes in English and take the short time needed to complete the survey!

http://app.fluidsurveys.com/s/british-schools-group/langeng/


2. A Small Request
A member of our staff is seeking an opportunity during the summer break and it occurred to me that with the positions of responsibility that our parent body hold, it might be possible that you may be able to support. Please see the request attached to this e-mail.


3. Diamond Jubilee Celebration June 10th


Preparations continue for our “Street Party” event. We are all hoping that the weather smiles upon us that day. If the weather is kind, do remember the sun cream and hats as it will be held outdoors and shade is limited. Talking of hats please see the attached poster advertising our school Hat Parade. While it will not be a competition, the parade will offer the opportunity to earn house-points for your team total this year!

Also, see the attached programme of events and times. The afternoon will begin with a picnic including activities and stalls, beginning at 1:15pm. It promises to be a great, informal family event and we hope to see you there!




4. Events reminder


With only four weeks to go and a busy schedule ahead, I just wanted to remind you of the major dates to insert into your diaries:


Tues 5th- Fri 8th

Tottenham Hotspur Football Camp

Confirmed students only Y1-3 9:00- 11:00 Y4-9 1:15- 3:15

Thurs 7th

Nursery Performance 9:30am

Sunday 10th

ISM Diamond Jubilee Street Party: Noon- 4pm

Wed 13th

ASAs end for the year

Thurs 14th

Y6-9 Maths/Science Fair 1:00 – 3:30

Fri 15th

UC Sports Day 9-12:00 pm

Y1-4 Olympic Theme begins

Sat 16th

ISM Open Golf competition- venue to be confirmed

Mon 18-Wed 20

Senior production 6pm each night

Wed 20

Y2 Production 9:30 am

Thurs 21

Y2 Production 6:00 pm

Friday 22

LS Sports Day 9-12:00 Final Reports go out

Tues 26th

Year 1- 3 Golf Competition (LC)

Parent Teacher Consultations 4-6pm

Wednesday 27th

Parent Teacher Consultation 4-6pm

Thursday 28th

Nursery Graduation 10:00am.

Friday 29th

Speech Day 10-12:00 am at The Ritz Carlton</textOnly>
    <type>html</type>
    <uiType>Aloha</uiType>
</EmailTemplate>
